[Subtitles by danielsangeo]
What?
What's going on?
I-I fe...I feel weird.
I don't trust these Doritos.
I think I've got bad nachos.
How does this happen?
There should be enough preservatives
in these things to mummify a small dog.
I need to find a phone
so I can call their hotline.
Tell 'em I've got bad nachos.
And the building's
being attacked by aliens.
Eh, I'll just stick with nachos.
Man, I'm getting déjà vu.
Where am I going?
Well, there can't be
anything good in that office
if that guy was diving out of
the window.
I guess that means I have to
take the elevator.
take the elevator!
God dammit.
This is exactly why you have stairs!
Stairs without turret guns!
Now why is there no ladder here?
The other shaft had a ladder here.
It was progressive.
Well, there's a ladder on the other side.
Oh, it's some sort of new age
Chutes and Ladders design.
So, my only way out of here is
to take some flying leap of faith.
Like that scene in
Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade.
Then claw like a mad cat
and hope like hell,
I get a grip, and don't break my ribs.
Once again, I need a grappling hook.
I can't believe this.
Why do you have a ladder
in an elevator shaft?
To fix the elevator.
How do you get to the ladder?
You take the elevator that doesn't work!
Who thought this one up?!
Jesus Christ!
I suppose I could do the math on
whether this jump is feasible or not,
but, y'know, I'll have plenty of
time for that when I'm dead.
Urf.
OH MY GOD!
That was stupid!
Why do I keep doing stupid things?
Oh my God...oh...
I could've died!
SCIENTIST: I...I...can't
hold on...much longer...
Oh, cry me a river!
I just jumped across an elevator shaft
onto a ladder, and I'm still here!
Do I look like Spiderman to you?
No!  If I was Spiderman, I could
do that web-flinging crap
and have been out of here hours ago.
The point is, you can learn
how to do a pull-up.
Although, I'll admit, these ledges suck.
I don't understand how--Whoa!
You might want to g--
[scientist screams]
[thud]
Never mind.
But yeah, I don't understand why
these ledges are so damned small.
There's like just enough
room to inch along here.
These things are designed
for Oompa Loompas.
I bet that's how management
thinks the elevators run.
A bunch of Oompa Loompas inside the shaft,
singing while they move ropes and pulleys.
[whistles Oompa Loompa song]
What the hell, what the hell,
what the hell...?
These ledges don't even reach the
floor the elevator's stopped on.
What's the point of even having them?
And why are they sloped downward?
As the professor showed us, it's easy
enough to die without the extra help.
Like this!
[exhale]
Huhh...thank you for not collapsing.
Though, I can't say I was
too worried about that,
seeing as how the other guy was
doing a flexed-armed hang here
for at least five minutes.
What was he doing there?
Is anyone hiding up there?
No...
Well....
Eh, too bad nobody's inside.
I bet I would've scared
the crap out of them.
Okay, this door better open or
else I'm going to kill somebody.
All right!
Now, nobody needs to die unless
I think of another reason.
Oh, I like this solid hallway
with no ledges.
Y'know, I think I just don't
feel like climbing anymore.
SCIENTIST: For God's sake!
Open the silo door!
SCIENTIST: They're coming for us!
What's going on?
SCIENTIST: It's our only way out!
SCIENTIST: Oh my God, we're doomed!
Yeah! Kick his ass!
No, you're doing it wrong!
[explosion]
Huh?
Yeah!  Shoot it!
Aww...
You people never fail
to disappoint me.
Why was that guy screaming about
the silo door?  It's closed.
Well, that shotgun's mine.
Oh, come ON!
There's extra ammo there and everything.
Well, I guess out of the whole facility,
the security station is the one place
that should have bulletproof glass.
But still, I could argue that I
have more need for a shotgun now
than any other time in my life.
Though, it wouldn't be the first
time I've said that.
Why is this guy dead?
He wasn't dead a minute ago.
He was screaming about silo
doors like a possessed farmer.
Did the laser kill him?
Are these death lasers?
They can't be that potent; his
body's not on fire.
I'm going to touch it.
[chirping sound]
[whistling sound]
Well, that didn't hurt.
[turret beeping]
What's going on?
[turret firing]
Ah-ah!
[turret beeping]
Of course!
A machine-gun turret.
[turret beeping]
Silly me, I forget how
we need these things.
[turret firing]
[turret beeping]
Yep, somewhere some manager's
feeling like less of a man
[turret beeping]
unless he buys more turret guns.
[turret firing]
[turret beeping]
Ow!
I can't even see what I'm shooting at.
[turret firing]
Ow!  Shit!  Fuck!
[turret beeping]
This is worse than paintball!
[teleportation sound]
Oh, great timing.
[turret firing]
[turret beeping]
Huh, well, at least it's nondiscriminatory
in what it shoots at.
[turret beeping]
All the more reason
NOT TO HAVE THEM IN THE FIRST PLACE!
[turret beeping]
Oh, and what's this?  A dead soldier!
This is exactly what I said
[turret beeping]
was going to happen!
Dead rescue team!
That'll teach you to beep at me.
I break alarm clocks, I can break you, too.
So, what's the story on this guy?
Yep, deader than a dead dead guy.
Is that an MP5?
It is!
Oh-ho-ho-ho-ho!
Now I can solve up to 800
problems a minute.
A submachine gun.
It's not just for party tricks.
[teleportation sound]
Allow me to demonstrate!
Ah-ha-ha-ha-ha...
That's right, short controlled bursts.
The candle that burns twice as
bright lasts half as long.
[teleportation sound]
Y'know, it's a marvel of science,
but this random teleportation
thing is getting old
[teleportation sound]
real fast.
Jesus Christ! Just keep them
coming, why don't ya?
Now, what is this?
I'm not sure, but I'm finding
that crossing these lasers
doesn't lead to anything good.
Hup!
And another!
I can limbo this.
I thought I shouldn't be able to
see the laser beam;
it had to be smoky or something.
Hm.
Oh, goodie.  Another dead guy.
I'd better conserve on the MP5.
[teleportation sound]
[vortigaunt charging up]
C'mon!
[vortigaunt bolt]
[shuddering]
Fucker...
[vortigaunt charging up]
P.A.: Turret maintenance team to
Central Command and
Communication Center.
Ah-ha-ha-ha.
[vortigaunt charging up]
Hey!
I think that intercom said
'Turret maintenance to center command'.
Yeah, I bet they have a few
questions to answer.
Like, why are our turret guns
killing off everyone in the building?
Man, they knew what they were
doing when they built this suit.
I must've taken a dozen bullets
and it hasn't even punctured it.
I'm really wishing I'd found that helmet.
Okay, let's NOT trip this laser.
[teleportation sound]
No!  Shut up, shut up, shut up!
Stay on your side of the line!
My roommate in college
used to do the same thing.
[teleportation sound]
If I had a gun then, I'd--
What did I just say?!
Huh?!
[vortigese]
That's right!  Stay on your side.
Your side is the one where everyone
is dead and there are no exits.
My side is the one filled with
hope, love and submachine guns.
And cargo hooks.
All right, is anyone looking?
Okay, here we go.
[Tarzan yell]
[teleportation sound]
[headcrabs squeal]
Oh, c'mon!
Why'd you have to spoil the moment?
[growls]
YOU GUYS HAVE NO APPRECIATION FOR ART!
[teleportation sound]
CRITIC!
You know, we're the ones
that invented teleporters...
...I think.
The least you could do is show a
little appreciation around here.
Yuck, I hate to say it, but with all
these sentry guns and laser tripwires,
I can't shake the feeling that
I'm going the wrong way again.
I mean, let's face it: you don't put
turret guns in the visitor's center.
Or the labs.
Or any other place you
want people to stay alive.
Isn't that the point of hiring
security guards?
They're smart enough to know not
to shoot everyone?
The crazy thing is, I may have been
doing the right thing all along.
That turret gun must have mowed
down that soldier.
I would've been waiting for a
rescue team that wasn't gonna make it.
Whoa, this is slick.
It's like there's oil mixed in
or something.
Whoa...
Oh, oh, nice.
Have an empty elevator shaft for
me to slide my ass into
after hopping over another tripwire.
That's great.
Oh, I see.  That was just one
stage of trying to kill me.
SCIENTIST: Hello there.
Uh... hi.
Little busy here.
Don't try to help me or anything.
'cuz nobody does that.
SCIENTIST: I'll stay here.
You do that!
God, you two are creeping me out.
"Come play with us, Gordon.
Forever...and ever...and ever..."
SCIENTIST: Do you know who ate
all the doughnuts?
"The doughn--"?  No!
I have more important things on my mind.
Okay, this is weird.
I'm going to need a
minute to think about this.
SCIENTIST: Fascinating!  I never
suspected such things could be.
Quit staring at me!
Yeah, you!